RAMKANNA'S RESUME



PERSONAL STATEMENT:

I have 3 degrees related to Engineering [B.E.(India), M.Sc.(Europe), and Adv Diploma(Portugal)]. After my Bachelors (for the past 13 years), I have a total of 4.5 years (various short span) of experiences from different companies. [Volunteering, travel, breaks periods—about 5 years, Studies period—3.5 years]

I am presently looking for a career change. I am interested to start a new career with any Company/Organisation/Foundation/NGO involved in sustainable management and development of various areas/fields/activities. I am open to take up any position such as Management support/Coordination support/Team member/Any position with your esteemed organisation.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

First name / Surname
Present Address
Telephone, E-mails
Nationality, D.o.B
Marital status

Ramkanna / Venkatachalam

8, 54th street, Ashok Nagar, Chennai – 600083, India +91-8015196095, <u>ramkanna19@gmail.com</u>, <u>ramkanna@mail.com</u> India, 19th June 1985 Single

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Total [btw 2007 – 2020] – Work experience – 4 years and 6 months [Volunteering, travel, breaks periods– about 5 years, Studies period – 3.6 years]

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities

Service Coordinator, from Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Coordinating activities (machines & equipment service activities),
- Helping and assisting medical technicians in various department activities

Name & address of employer

Type of business

Tamil Nadu Government Multi Super Specality Hospital (hired by contract agency) Medical

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities Name &address of employer Type of business

Inside Sales Executive, May 2018 - July 2018

Calling clients for business development, - coordination activities
 Esync Security Solutions, Chennai, India
 CCTV camera projects, all types of electronic security systems, etc.

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities

Intern - Solar Energy & Smart Grids, Aug 2014 - Jan 2015

- Vendor companies networking (Smart Energy, Solar Energy, etc.) to gather information, - Insights into Project feasibility studies

Rukshaya Emerging Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India Consulting

Name &address of employer

Type of business

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities

Project team member, Apr 2013 - Aug 2013

Assisting for renewable energy projects.

- 1. Energy part for White paper on Green campus,
- $2. \ Overseeing \ Office \ Hybrid \ RE \ system (acting as an interface for the installation of office energy management automation system).$
- 3. Solar Photovoltaic System Installation training programs.

Name & address of employer

Auroville Consulting, Auroville, India

Type of business

Consulting

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities Trainee Consultant - Renewable Energy, Feb 2011 - Jun 2011

Market survey and report preparation for a German solar inverter company for transferring their technology to India. To make collaboration between Indian Universities and our company to set up centres to do research, consultancy work, transfer of technology, trainings, etc.

Name & address of employer Type of business Steinbeis Centre for Technology Transfer India, Hyderabad, India.

Consulting, Technology Transfer

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities Trainee, Apr 2010 - Jul 2010

My task was to work in a team to design and install two types solar power plant for display. I got to work with different nationalities and got exposure to all types of renewable energy, technology transfer to community, etc.

Name & address of employer Type of business Folkecenter - Centre for Renewable Energy, Ydby, Denmark.

Renewable Energy, Technology Transfer

Position held. Dates Main responsibilities Student job - Research work, Jan-Apr & Jun 2008

On-campus (university laboratory) research work on operating parameters of OSRAM lamps. Measurement and data collection of various lamp's operating &starting voltages and other related parameters.

Name & address of employer Type of business Osram GmbH, Augsburg, Germany

Lighting industry

Position held, Dates Main responsibilities Project associate, Dec 2006 - May 2007

Development and testing of software for Electrical circuit simulation & report making.

Name & address of employer Type of business Department of EEE, College of Engineering Guindy, Anna University, Chennai, India

Education / Academics

HOSPITALITY EXPERIENCES:

Position held, Dates

Volunteering (Travel) & Part-time job, July 2016 - Oct 2016

Bed making, Arranging breakfasts, Cleaning, occasionally help at bar & reception Main responsibilities Company & location, (Business)

Hub New Hostel, Lisbon, Portugal, (Hostel, Travel, Tourism)

Position held, Dates

Holiday Part-time job, July-August 2015

Main responsibilities Cleaning, cutting vegetables, assisting the Chef in the kitchen Company & location, (Business) 'Restaurante A Tricana', Coimbra, Portugal, (Food, Restaurant)

EDUCATION & TRAINING:

Title of Qualification, Dates

Specialization Diploma in Energy for Sustainability (Score - 13.6/20), Mar'15 - July'16

Name of Institute

Faculty of Science & Technology, University of Coimbra, Portugal

Title of Qualification, Dates

Solar PV Energy Systems Design, Installation, Engg.& Management, Feb 2-22, 2013

Name of the institute

FESPL Florance Institute of Renewable Energy Technology, Chennai, India

Title of qualification, Dates

M.Sc. - Functionalized Advanced Materials & Engg. (Score - 70%), Oct 2007 - Nov 2009

Principal subjects/occupational skills

Material science - Material Physics, Material Chemistry, Material Processing, Material Characterisation techniques, etc.

Also learned & got training for presentation & other soft-skills from my supervisor

Name of the institute

Year 1 – University of Augsburg, Germany, Year 2 – University of Aveiro, Portugal

Title of qualification, Dates

B.E. - Electrical and Electronics Engineering (Score - 70%), Aug 2002 - May 2006

Principal subjects/occupational skills

Principal: Electrical and Electronics Engineering; Basics of Mechanical, Civil, etc. Principles of Management, Professional Ethics, Total Quality Management

Name of the institute

MNM Jain Engineering College, Affiliated to Anna University, Chennai, India

Title of qualification, Dates

Higher Secondary Course - Std.12 - School final yr (Score - 86%), Jun 2001 - Mar 2002

Principal subjects

Principal subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology

Languages: English, Tamil

Name of the institute

Little Flower Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai, India

PERSONAL SKILLS & **COMPETENCES:**

Languages

Mother tongue Fluency in Basic knowledge

Tamil English

Hindi, German, Portuguese

Social skills

- Adaptability, Appreciation of beauty and excellence
- Friendly, easy going, cooperative
- Appreciation of different cultures, languages, etc.
- As a Holiday Travel I volunteered to work for a UK family in Algarve, Portugal for a week in December, 2008
- National Service Scheme, Red-cross Volunteer when studying in school
- 'Teach for India', 1 month(2012) as a volunteer at a Government school-4th std

Organisational skills

- Ability to deal with people diplomatically and a good team player
- Curiosity to learn new things and Creativity
- Working for tangible results with attentiveness and dedication

Artistic skills

- Active member of my college Symposium and Cultural organizing committee
- Dancing, Painting, Mimicry (Have participated in the school and college level competitions and have won prizes)

Other skills

- Cricket, Badminton, Volleyball (Have represented the school and college team)
- Like Swimming, Music, Travelling, Yoga and practice occasionally
- Level 1 German language, Goethe institute certification
- Basic course on Portuguese language, University of Aveiro